<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<!-- This is a WordPress eXtended RSS file generated by WordPress as an export of your site. -->
<!-- It contains information about your site's posts, pages, comments, categories, and other content. -->
<!-- You may use this file to transfer that content from one site to another. -->
<!-- This file is not intended to serve as a complete backup of your site. -->

<!-- To import this information into a WordPress site follow these steps: -->
<!-- 1. Log in to that site as an administrator. -->
<!-- 2. Go to Tools: Import in the WordPress admin panel. -->
<!-- 3. Install the "WordPress" importer from the list. -->
<!-- 4. Activate & Run Importer. -->
<!-- 5. Upload this file using the form provided on that page. -->
<!-- 6. You will first be asked to map the authors in this export file to users -->
<!--    on the site. For each author, you may choose to map to an -->
<!--    existing user on the site or to create a new user. -->
<!-- 7. WordPress will then import each of the posts, pages, comments, categories, etc. -->
<!--    contained in this file into your site. -->

<!-- generator="WordPress/4.4.2" created="2016-03-28 20:38" -->
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:excerpt="http://wordpress.org/export/1.2/excerpt/"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:wp="http://wordpress.org/export/1.2/"
>

<channel>
	<title>Carina C. Zona</title>
	<link>http://cczona.com/blog</link>
	<description>See. Do. Teach.</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 28 Mar 2016 20:38:03 +0000</pubDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<wp:wxr_version>1.2</wp:wxr_version>
	<wp:base_site_url>http://cczona.com/blog</wp:base_site_url>
	<wp:base_blog_url>http://cczona.com/blog</wp:base_blog_url>

	<wp:author><wp:author_id>1</wp:author_id><wp:author_login><![CDATA[admin]]></wp:author_login><wp:author_email><![CDATA[cczona@gmail.com]]></wp:author_email><wp:author_display_name><![CDATA[admin]]></wp:author_display_name><wp:author_first_name><![CDATA[Carina C.]]></wp:author_first_name><wp:author_last_name><![CDATA[Zon]]></wp:author_last_name></wp:author>


	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.4.2</generator>

	<item>
		<title>About</title>
		<link>http://cczona.com/blog/about/</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 23 Sep 2011 06:12:40 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cczona.com/blog/?page_id=2</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2><strong>Carina C. Zona</strong> <em>(cczona)</em></h2>
<p>Carina is a web developer based in northern California.</p>
<p><a href="http://cczona.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2011/09/headshot.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-thumbnail wp-image-64" title="Headshot with pink hair" src="http://cczona.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2011/09/headshot-150x150.jpg" alt="Headshot of me with short pink hair" width="150" height="150" /></a></p>]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>6</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2011-09-23 06:12:40]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2011-09-23 06:12:40]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[about]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[page]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wp_page_template]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[default]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Talk Abstracts</title>
		<link>http://cczona.com/blog/talks/</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 07 Sep 2012 13:52:55 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cczona.com/blog/?page_id=473</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<dl id="talks">


<dt><h2>Consequences of an Insightful Algorithm</h2></dt>

<dd>
    <aside class="pullquotes" style="color:red">
        <p><q><br><br><a href="https://twitter.com/halfbyte/status/648176174443724800">A well delivered lesson hitting close to home</a></q></p>
        <p><q><br><br><a href="https://twitter.com/MathildeMouw/status/665931361451008000">Insightful, motivating &amp; haunting</a></q></p>
        <p><q><br><br><a href="https://twitter.com/scott_triglia/status/627626016802865152">Required for anyone doing deep learning/machine learning</a></q></p>
        <p><q><br><br><a href="https://lixue95.wordpress.com/2016/01/17/social-responsibility-in-software-engineering/">Profoundly changed my thinking</a></q></p>
        <p><q><br><br><a href="https://twitter.com/rosieodsey/status/627627831040720896">Makes you want to throw up, cry, punch a wall...and change the world</a></q></p>
    </aside>
</dd>    
    


<dd>
<em>
RubyConf (keynote), JsConfEU (keynote), PyConAU (keynote), Open Source Bridge (keynote), CUSEC (keynote), WDCNZ, DjangoCon, ArrrrCamp, Lean Agile Scotland, All Things Open
</em>
</dd>

<dd>
<p>
We have ethical responsibilities when coding. We’re able to extract remarkably precise intuitions about an individual. But do we have a right to know what they didn’t consent to share, even when they willingly shared the data that leads us there? A major retailer’s data-driven marketing accidentially revealed to a teen’s family that she was pregnant. Eek.
</p>

<p>
What are our obligations to people who did not expect themselves to be so intimately known without sharing directly? How do we mitigate against unintended outcomes? For instance, an activity tracker carelessly revealed users’ sexual activity data to search engines. A social network’s algorithm accidentally triggered painful memories for grieving families who’d recently experienced death of their child and other loved ones.
</p>

<p>
We design software for humans. Balancing human needs and business specs can be tough. It’s crucial that we learn how to build in systematic empathy.
</p>

<p>
In this talk, we’ll delve into specific examples of uncritical programming, and painful results from using insightful data in ways that were benignly intended. You’ll learn ways we can integrate practices for examining how our code might harm individuals. We’ll look at how to flip the paradigm, netting consequences that can be better for everyone.
</p>


<dd>
    <p>
      <small>45 minutes</small>
    </p>
  <p>
<dd>

<dd>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=NheE6udjfGI">
         VIDEO
     </a>, 

     <a href="http://www.slideshare.net/cczona/consequences-of-an-insightful-algorithm">
        SLIDES
     </a>, 

     <a href="https://storify.com/cczona/consequences-of-an-insightful-algorithm">REVIEWS</a>
</dd>




  <dt>
    <h2>Schemas for the Real World</h2>
   </dt>
   
  <dd>
   <em>
   PyCon, OSCON, PHP[tek], Software Craftsmanship North America, Madison RubyConf, PyConAU, RailsConf, RubyConfAU, GoGaRuCo
   </em>
  <dd> 

<dd>
      <p>Social app development challenges us to code for users' personal world. Users are giving push-back to ill-fitted assumptions about their own identity - name, gender, sexual orientation, important relationships, and many other attributes that are individually meaningful.</p>

      <p>How can we balance users' realities with an app's business requirements?</p>

      <p>Facebook, Google+, OkCupid, LinkedIn, Flickr and others are struggling with these questions. Resilient approaches arise from an app's own foundation. Discover how our earliest choices influence codebase, UX, and development itself. Learn how we can use that knowledge to both inspire the people who use our apps, and to generate the data that we need as developers.</p>
</dd>  

<dd>
    <p>
      <small>45 minutes</small>
    </p>
  <p>
<dd>

<dd>
<a href="http://vimeo.com/80375707">
         VIDEO
     </a>, 

     <a href="http://www.slideshare.net/cczona/schemas-for-the-real-world-snca-2013-by-carina-c-zona-28073769">
        SLIDES
     </a>, 

     <a href="http://storify.com/cczona/schemas-for-the-real-world/">REVIEWS</a>
</dd>



<dt>
<h2>Converged Cloud Computing That's Secure, Fast, or Cheap: Pick Three</h2>
<dt>

<dd>
<em>
OpenStack Summit
</em>
</dd>

<dd>
<p>Containers are driving down the overhead that has been necessary for traditional virtualization. But there have been serious tradeoffs made with their adoption. Containerization's resource sharing approach is exposing more of the host system. We're choosing to compromise the isolation of executables from kernel, accepting it as an inevitable price for low overhead. In multi-tenant environments, that's a heck of a gamble.</p>

<p>Tightrope acts like that do not need to happen.</p> 

<p>ZeroVM has taken an entirely distincive approach to lightweight virtualization: strong security, from the beginning. Processes are kept on lockdown, jobs are horizontally scalable, and they execute with such fine-grained accuracy that metering by the second is no problem. End the cost-inefficiencies of metering by minutes and hours.</p>

<p>ZeroVM provides a secure execution environment for untrusted code, by applying the Chromium project's proven Native Client (NaCl) technology for validation and sandboxing. Moreover, when paired with OpenStack Swift, the two become a unique platform for executing arbitrary queries within a datastore, using any language of one's choosing.</p>

<p>We'll walk through the basics of the ZeroVM open source project, compelling use cases, and opportunities to take advantage of ZeroVM + Swift -- for solving problems at scale without compromising on either security, speed, or affordability.</p>
</dd>

<dd>
    <p>
      <small>40 minutes</small>
    </p>
  <p>
<dd>




<dt>
<h2>
Debugging Tech's Class Social Justice Issues
</h2>
</dt>

<dd>
<em>
Madison+ Ruby, Distill
</em>
</dd>

<dd>
As developers, we have power to be constructors of social justice. If we are members of tech community, then we inherit a chain of responsibility for addressing intersections between our work and its sometimes profoundly local effects on communities. We can choose to engage in debugging and fixes. We start by engaging in introspection about the inequities that our industry imposes on groups who have fewer privileges than we have access to. We’re going to walk through some of these issues, and review methods for implementing change.
</dd>

<dd>
    <p>
      <small>30 minutes</small>
    </p>
  <p>
<dd>


<dt>
<h2>
Doctor, Lawyer, Poker Player, Physicist: The Best Engineers We're Not Competing To Hire Yet
</h2>
<dt>

<dd>
<em>
Lone Star PHP, Kod.io
</em>
</dd>

<dd>
<p>
The team needs more engineers and we need them today. We talk about the engineer shortage.
</p>

<p>
But the problem is not what we think it is. We’ll explore how hiring for only CS degrees misses exceptional opportunities.
</p>

<p>
Unconventional backgrounds breed great developers. Homogeneity boxes us in. Diverse teams are more productive, more profitable, and more excited about what they’re accomplishing. Diversity isn’t just demographics. It’s about benefitting from distinctly varied perspectives.
</p>

<p>
Who better than the former philosopher, marine biologist, stage hand, or anthropologist?
</p>

<p>
In this talk, we’ll walk through why it’s worth competing for them. Forget the rock star; hire the opera singer.
</p>

</dd>

<dd>
    <p>
      <small>30 minutes</small>
    </p>
  <p>
<dd>


<dt>
  <h2>Handcrafting Community</h2>
</dt>

<dd>
   <em>
  <p>Burlington RubyConf, Steel City RubyConf</p>
  </em>
</dd>

<dd>
<p>Community-building can seem like a herculean effort that must be coordinated among many.  But it doesn't have to be.  One is plenty.  

<p>How can we handcraft a fulfilling code career?  How can we support peers in developing theirs, whether newcomer or artisan?  How can we contribute, without having to be expert?  How do we develop social capital among community members, and channel those investments into people who are just entering? How will we craft a thriving community, using only simple tools & scarce local resources?

<p>We'll examine the history of major successes -- in Ruby community, Python, and well beyond -- and extract lessons to apply generally. It's a story that weaves in personal narratives of rising into that, both well and clumsily.  It's about transforming minor ambitions & frequent iterations into a scope of change that looks amazing. By making choices to do small things well and thoughtfully, rather than with concern for how they scale.
</dd>

<dd>
  <p class="talk-length">
    <small>30 minutes</small>
  </p>

</dd>


<!-- next -->
<dt>
  <h2> Doctor, Lawyer, Poker Player, Physicist: The Best Engineers We're Not Competing To Hire Yet</h2>
 </dt>
 
<dd>
<em>
Lone Star PHP, Kod.io
</em>
</dd>

<dd>
  <p>"The team needs more engineers and we need them today."</p>

  <p>We talk about the engineer shortage. But the problem is not what we think it is. We'll explore how hiring for only CS degrees misses exceptional opportunities. Unconventional backgrounds breed great developers.</p>

  <p>Homogeneity boxes us in. Diverse teams are more productive, more profitable, and more excited about what they're accomplishing. Diversity isn't just demographics. It's about benefitting from distinctly varied perspectives. Who better than the former philosopher, marine biologist, stage hand, or anthropologist? In this talk, we'll walk through why it's worth competing for them.</p>

  <p>Forget the rock star; hire the opera singer.</p>

<dd>

<dd>
  <p class="talk-length">
    <small>30 minutes</small>
  </p>
</dd>


  <!--next-->
 <dt>
  <h2>The Evil Overlords' Guide to Being a Senior Developer</h2>
 </dt>
 
<dd>

  <dd>
    <em>Fluent</em>
  </dd>

  <dd>

  <p>Hollywood super villains learn their lessons the hard way. You don't have to. What can we learn about doing good, from thwarted forces of doom?</p>

  <p>It's been said that coders "stand on the shoulders of giants." We'll take a session to stand on the shoulders of legendary tyrants, get a view from their side, & discover how to lead with the humor and grace that perpetually evades those gals and guys.</p>

 </dd>

<!-- next -->

  <dt class="">
    <h2>Full-Stack &amp; Full Circle: What The Heck Happens in An HTTP Request, and Why It’s Worth Knowing</h2>
  </dt>

  <dd>
    <em>Confident Coding III</em>
  </dd>

  <dd>
    <p>Flying in from 10,000 foot view ("Hey, browser, show me this", "Okay, here it is"), we'll take thoughtful overview of the HTTP request/response cycle.  Its essence is simply a series of questions &amp; answers, accumulating portions of content to be gracefully assembled for the user.
    <p>We'll hone in on some key players amidst the "full stack" of communications, with special attention to how an understanding of the HTTP lifecycle endows any developer or designer with the power to optimize for performance, cost, and UX</p>
  </dd>

  <dd>
    <p class="talk-length">
      <small>30 minutes</small>
    </p>
  </dd>
 


  <dt>
    <h2>Cool Git Tricks (That I Learn When Things Go Badly)</h2>
  </dt>

  <dd>
 <em>Women Who Code</em>
  </dd>

  <dd>
      <p>A quick and cheeky intro to some very handy features that even experienced users are frequently unaware of.</p>

    <p class="talk-length">
      <small>6 minutes (part 1) & 7 minutes (part 2)</small>
    </p>
  </dd>

</dl>]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>473</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2012-09-07 13:52:55]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2012-09-07 13:52:55]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[talks]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[page]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wp_page_template]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[default]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Workshops</title>
		<link>http://cczona.com/blog/teaching/</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 21 Sep 2012 21:41:18 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cczona.com/blog/?page_id=502</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="workshops-list">

<h3>Original Content</h3>

  <dt>Enspiral DevAcademy Wellington</dt>
  <dd>
Data Modeling The Hard Way: A Q&A
<span class="course-type">(90 minute workshop)</span>
</dd>

  <dt>Women Who Code San Francisco</dt>
  <dd>
Things Nobody Told Us About Conference Speaking
<em>co-presenter</em>
<span class="course-type">(2 hour workshop)</span>
</dd>

  <dt>Twitter Women in Engineering</dt>
  <dd>
Interpreting Calls for Proposals: A Q&A
<span class="course-type">(2 hour workshop)</span>
</dd>

  <dt>Rackspace OSCON Booth</dt>
  <dd>
ZeroVM 101
<span class="course-type">(30 minute presentation)</span>
</dd>

  <dt>Girl Develop It Chicago & Enspiral DevAcademy Wellington</dt>
  <dd>
<a href="http://www.meetup.com/Girl-Develop-It-Chicago-IL/events/184039012/">Proposing Your First Conference Talk</a>
<span class="course-type">(2 hour workshop)</span>
</dd>

  <dt>DevBootcamp San Francisco</dt>
  <dd>
Technical Speaking for Job, Fun, & Profit
<span class="course-type">(1 hour presentation)</span>

</dd>


  <dt>WebDev42 Hobart</dt>
  <dd>Building Tech Communities Locally
<span class="course-type">(2 hour workshop)</span>
</dd>

  <dt>RailsBridge</dt>
  <dd>
Ruby for Beginners <em>curriculum author</em>
<span class="course-type">(7 hour workshop)</em>
</dd>
  
  <dt>Women Who Code San Francisco</dt>
  <dd>
<a href="http://www.meetup.com/Women-Who-Code-SF/events/93217172/">Women Who Code Who Do Tech Talks Too</a> <em>panel moderator</em>
<span class="course-type">(3 hour panel/workshops)</span>
</dd>

  <dt>PyLadies San Francisco</dt>
  <dd>
Git Essentials
<span class="course-length">(2 hour workshop)</span>
</dd>

  <dt>Girl Develop It San Francisco</dt>
  <dd>
Git &amp; Bash Essentials
<span class="course-length">(5 hour workshop)</span>
</dd>

</dl>

</div>


<hr/>


<h3>3rd-Party Content</h3>

<p>I primarily create original workshops and lectures these days, however these are workshops that I've taught in the past using others' curricula:</p>

<dl>
  <dt>RailsBridge</dt>
  <dd>Ruby on Rails <span class="course-length">(8 hours)</span></dd>
  <dd>HTML &amp; CSS <span class="course-length">(5 hours)</span></dd>
  <dd>Ruby <span class="course-length">(curriculum principal author)</span></dd>

  <dt>RailsGirls</dt>
  <dd>Ruby on Rails <span class="course-length">(8 hours)</span></dd>

  <dt>Black Girls Code</dt>
  <dd>Product Development <span class="course-length">(5 hours)</span></dd>

  <dt>GetSET</dt>
  <dd>Ruby, HTML, CSS <span class="course-length">(5 hours; TA)</span></dd>

</dl>]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>502</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2012-09-21 14:41:18]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2012-09-21 21:41:18]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[teaching]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[page]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wp_page_template]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[default]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>More Abstracts</title>
		<link>http://cczona.com/blog/abstracts/</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 14 Jan 2013 02:35:57 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cczona.com/blog/?page_id=609</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In addition to <a href="talks">talks I've given previously</a>, these are available by request:</p>

<hr/>

<h3> 1 Factor, 2 Factor, Red Factor, Blue Factor: Doubling Up On Security with Two Factor Authentication</h3>

<p>In this beginner-level talk you'll learn about the various forces that are driving adoption of multi-factor authentication including 2FA. We'll look at why certain solutions have become especially popular. We’ll discuss the challenges of applying “something you are” factors such as biometrics. We'll compare the pros and cons of a wide gamut of "something you have" approaches, including SMS, voice calls, card readers, thumbdrives, grids, soft tokens, hard tokens. We'll candidly evaluate ease of implementation, ease-of-use, and potential trouble spots.</p>

<hr/>

<h3>Rock That Q&A: Pro Tips for Speakers, Audiences, and Hosts</h3>

<p>Q&A rocks! It's an opportunity for listeners to clarify what's they've heard and engage deeper with content. Speakers gain valuable interactive feedback, and learn which points are worth elaborating on next time. Yet many of us are wary of Q&A. "What if I mis-speak?" "What if there are hecklers?" "What if I don't have all the answers?" They're understandable concerns. Mastering the art of Q&A allows us to fearlessly embrace that uncertainty.</p>

<p>As developers, we're constantly educating; as speakers, instructors, authors, mentors, team members, and event organizers. When we can deftly rock Q&A, we deliver extra value in all of those roles. </p>

<p>Productive Q&A arises from enthusiastic collaboration between speaker, audience, and host; in this talk, you'll learn skills for each role. We'll delve into setting expectations, selecting among various formats, keeping Q&A focused and on-time, dealing with complicated questions, counteracting attempts to derail, and using Q&A as excellent foundation for follow-up discussions, networking, and lead generation.</p>

<hr/>

<h3>Cool Git Tricks (...That I Learn When Things Go Badly)</h3>

<p>A cheeky tour of ridiculously handy features that even experienced Git users are frequently unaware of.  No more blundering into trouble.  For me, that is.  You won’t have to blunder in the first case. You’ll discover the really cool features that make Git worth learning.</p>

<hr/>

<h3>Tech Innovation in Sexual Health Education</h3>

<p>Creative use of emerging technology is making human sexuality education fun to engage with and sustain. This session is rich with real-world examples using disparate technologies for internet & mobile, including: accelerometer, geolocation, APIs, SMS, crowdsourcing, open data, data visualization, gamification, social networking, and virtual worlds.</p>

<hr/>

<h3>Sex Education Hackers’ Guidebook for Every App Developer</h3>

<p>Innovative use of mobile, web, and gaming are making sex education fun to engage with! These developers are meeting challenges, and devising clever solutions that connect with diverse users worldwide. We'll take a whirlwind tour of apps, to uncover the surprising product development insights that startups in any field will find invaluable.</p>]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>609</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2013-01-13 18:35:57]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2013-01-14 02:35:57]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[abstracts]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[page]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wp_page_template]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[default]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Speaker</title>
		<link>http://cczona.com/blog/speaker/</link>
		<pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2013 00:14:18 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cczona.com/blog/?page_id=693</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<em>(Meta for conference organizers)</em>

<h2>Carina C. Zona</h2>

<h3>Bio</h3>
Carina C. Zona is a web developer and consultant.  She has taught for Girl Develop It, Black Girls Code, RailsBridge, PyLadies, and RailsGirls. She served on RailsBridge core team and Women Who Code core team. She is also a certified sex educator. In her spare time, she engineers baked goods.

<h3>Tech Conference Speaking Experience</h3>
Abstracts, videos, slides, and reviews of conference talks are at <a href="http://cczona.com/talks">http://cczona.com/talks</a>.

Moderator of the <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=yE67bo7dmbY">panel discussion "@WomenWhoCode Who Do Tech Talks Too"</a> recorded by O'Reilly Media.

<h3>Photo</h3>

<a class="thumbnail" href="http://cczona.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/carina-c-zona.jpg"><img src="http://cczona.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/carina-c-zona-150x150.jpg" alt="" title="carina-c-zona" width="150" height="150" class="alignnone size-thumbnail wp-image-694" /></a>

<a class="thumbnail" href="http://cczona.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/carina-c-zona.jpg"><img src="http://cczona.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/carina-c-zona-300x300.jpg" alt="" title="carina-c-zona" width="300" height="300" class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-694" /></a>

<a class="thumbnail" href="http://cczona.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/carina-c-zona.jpg"><img src="http://cczona.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/carina-c-zona.jpg" alt="" title="carina-c-zona" width="640" height="640" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-694" /></a>

]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>693</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2013-04-12 17:14:18]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2013-04-13 00:14:18]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[speaker]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[page]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wp_page_template]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[default]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Conferences</title>
		<link>http://cczona.com/blog/upcoming/</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2014 03:13:12 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cczona.com/blog/?page_id=760</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h3>Code of Conduct Pledge</h3>
I participate in a lot of conferences, and have <a href="https://twitter.com/cczona/status/380202566040027136">pledged</a> to only do so at conferences that have a Code of Conduct. Thus why the schedule below includes links to those. It's a <a href="https://twitter.com/cczona/status/425869040796454912">reminder</a> to you and me both that this is a genuine commitment for me. If I screw up, please do let me know. It's an opportunity to have good conversations with organizers.

Interested in learning more? Check out Ashe Dryden's <a href="http://www.ashedryden.com/blog/a-year-in-codes-of-conduct-at-tech-confs">pair</a> of <a href="http://www.ashedryden.com/blog/codes-of-conduct-101-faq">blog posts</a>, sign up at Julia Elman's <a href="http://www.letsgetlouder.com/">Let's Get Louder</a>, and browse my <a href="https://twitter.com/cocpledge">@cocpledge</a> aggregator to learn why other people say it matters for them too.

<a>Codes of conduct are a norm for hundreds of our communities' conferences</a>. I like that we all have opportunity to support their commitment, and to ask other conferences to appreciate that this is necessary and valuable.

<h3>2016 Conference Schedule</h3>
<ul>

<li>
<strong><a href="http://2016.cusec.net/">CUSEC</a></strong>
(<a href="http://2016.cusec.net/coc.html">code of conduct</a>).
<em>Keynote Speaker</em>
</li>

</ul>

<h3>2015 Conference Schedule</h3>
<ul>

<li>
<strong><a href="http://rubyconf.org/">RubyConf</a></strong>
(<a href="http://rubyconf.org/policies">code of conduct</a>).
<em>Keynote Speaker</em>
</li>



<li>
<strong><a href="http://allthingsopen.org/">All Things Open</a></strong>
(<a href="http://allthingsopen.org/code-of-conduct/">code of conduct</a>).
<em>Speaker</em>
</li>

<li>
<strong><a href="http://www.leanagilescotland.com/">Lean Agile Scotland</a></strong>
(<a href="http://www.leanagilescotland.com/code_of_conduct">code of conduct</a>).
<em>Speaker</em>
</li>

<li>
<strong><a href="arrrrcamp.be">ArrrrCamp</a></strong>
(<a href="http://2015.arrrrcamp.be/coc/">code of conduct</a>).
<em>Speaker</em>
</li>

<li>
<strong><a href="http://2015.jsconf.eu">JSConfEU</a></strong>
(<a href="http://2015.jsconf.eu/code-of-conduct">code of conduct</a>).
<em>Keynote Speaker</em>
</li>

<li>
<strong><a href="rejectjs.org">Reject.js</a></strong>
(<a href="http://rejectjs.org/#code_of_conduct">code of conduct</a>)
</li>

<li>
<strong><a href="https://2015.djangocon.us/">DjangoCon</a></strong>
(<a href="https://2015.djangocon.us/code_of_conduct/">code of conduct</a>).
<em>Speaker</em>
</li>

<li>
<strong><a href="http://www.devopsdays.org/events/2015-chicago/">DevOpsDays Chicago</a></strong>
(<a href="http://www.devopsdays.org/events/2015-chicago/conduct/">code of conduct</a>)
</li>

<li>
<strong><a href="madisonpl.us/ruby/">Madison+ Ruby</a></strong>
(<a href="http://madisonpl.us/ruby/code-conduct/">code of conduct</a>)
</li>

<li>
<strong><a href="https://www.andconf.io/">AndConf</a></strong>
(<a href="https://www.andconf.io/code_of_conduct">code of conduct</a>).
<em>Unconference session facilitator</em>
</li>

<li>
<strong><a href="http://2015.pycon-au.org/">PyConAU</a></strong>
(<a href="http://2015.pycon-au.org/register/code_of_conduct">code of conduct</a>).
<em>Keynote Speaker</em>
</li>

<li>
<strong><a href="http://wdcnz.com/">WDCNZ</a></strong>
(<a href="http://wdcnz.com/downloads/WDCNZ%20Code%20of%20Conduct%20_%20T&C's.pdf">code of conduct</a>).
<em>Speaker</em>
</li>

<li>
<strong>
<a href="http://www.alterconf.com/sessions/portland-or">AlterConf Portland</a>
</strong>
(<a href="http://www.alterconf.com/code-of-conduct">code of conduct, accessibility, etiquette</a>).
</li>

<li>
<strong><a href="http://opensourcebridge.org/">Open Source Bridge</a></strong>
(<a href="http://opensourcebridge.org/about/code-of-conduct/">code of conduct</a>).
<em>Keynote Speaker. Unconference session facilitator.</em>
</li>

<li>
<strong>
<a href="http://fluentconf.com/javascript-html-2015">Fluent</a>
</strong>
(<a href="http://www.oreilly.com/conferences/code-of-conduct.html">code of conduct</a>)
</li>

<li>
<strong>
<a href="http://montreal.adacamp.org/">AdaCamp Montreal</a>
</strong>
(<a href="http://montreal.adacamp.org/policies/">policies</a>)
</li>

<li>
<strong>
<a href="http://us.pycon.org/2015">PyCon</a>
</strong>
(<a href="http://us.pycon.org/2015/about/code-of-conduct/">code of conduct</a>).
<em>Speaker</em>
</li>

<li>
<strong>
<a href="https://www.eventbrite.com/event/13540462889">Developer Evangelist Summit</a>
</strong>
(Whoops, I forgot to check!).
</li>

<li>
<strong>
<a href="http://www.alterconf.com/sessions/sfoakland-ca">AlterConf Oakland</a>
</strong>
(<a href="http://www.alterconf.com/code-of-conduct">code of conduct, accessibility, etiquette</a>).
</li>


</ul>



<h3>2014 Conferences</h3>

<ul>

<li>
<strong><a href="https://www.openstack.org/summit/openstack-paris-summit-2014/">OpenStack Summit Paris</a></strong>
(<a href="https://www.openstack.org/summit/openstack-paris-summit-2014/code-of-conduct/">code of conduct</a>).
<em>Speaker</em>
</li>

<li>
<strong><a href="http://gogaruco.com/">GoGaRuCo</a></strong>
(<a href="http://gogaruco.com/about/">code of conduct</a>)
</li>

<li>
<strong><a href="http://madisonpl.us/ruby/">Madison+ Ruby</a></strong>
(<a href="http://madisonpl.us/ruby/code-conduct/">code of conduct</a>)
<em>Speaker</em>
</li>

<li>
<strong><a href="https://distill.engineyard.com/">Distill</a></strong>
("<a href="https://www.engineyard.com/community/anti-harassment-statement">anti-harassment policy</a>)
<em>Speaker</em>
</li>

<li>
<strong><a href="http://www.oscon.com/oscon2014">OSCON</a></strong>
(<a href="http://oreilly.com/conferences/code-of-conduct.html">code of conduct</a>)
<em>Speaker. Unconference session facilitator.</em>
</li>

<li>
<strong><a href="http://www.communityleadershipsummit.com">Community Leadership Summit</a></strong>
(<a href="http://www.communityleadershipsummit.com/about/harassment/">anti-harassment policy</a>)
<em>Unconference session facilitator.</em>
</li>

<li>
<strong><a href="http://radar.oreilly.com/2014/07/signals-from-foo-camp-2014.html">Foo Camp</a> </strong>
(<a href="http://www.oreilly.com/conferences/code-of-conduct.html">code of conduct</a>) 
<em>Unconference session facilitator</em>
</li>

<li>
<strong><a href="http://www.phparch.com">PHP[tek]</a></strong> 
(<a href="http://www.phparch.com/policies/code-of-conduct/">code of conduct</a>) 
<em>Speaker</em>
</li>

<li>
<strong><a href="https://www.openstack.org/summit/openstack-summit-atlanta-2014/">OpenStack Summit Atlanta</a></strong> 
(<a href="https://www.openstack.org/summit/openstack-summit-atlanta-2014/the-openstack-summit-code-of-conduct/">code of conduct</a>). 
</li>

<li>
<strong><a href="http://www.openwest.org/">OpenWest</a></strong> 
(<a href="http://www.openwest.org/code-of-conduct/">code of conduct</a>).
<em>Speaker</em>
</li>

<li>
<strong><a href="http://lonestarphp.com">LoneStar PHP</a></strong> 
(<a href="http://lonestarphp.com/code-of-conduct">code of conduct</a>). 
<em>Speaker</em>
</li>

<li>
<strong><a href="https://us.pycon.org/2014/">PyCon</a></strong> 
(<a href="https://us.pycon.org/2014/about/code-of-conduct/">code of conduct</a>).
<em>Unconference session facilitator</em>
</li>

<li>
<strong><a href="http://linz.kod.io/">Kod.io</a></strong> 
(<a href="http://linz.kod.io/">code of conduct</a>). 
<em>Speaker</em>
</li>

</ul>

<h3>Pre-pledge Conferences</h3>

<h4>2013</h4>

<ul>
<li>
Software Craftsmanship North America (SCNA). <em>Speaker</em>
</li>
<li>
Madison RubyConf. <em>Speaker</em>
</li>
<li>
Steel City RubyConf (code of conduct). <em>Speaker</em>
</li>
<li>
Burlington RubyConf. <em>Speaker</em>
</li>
<li>
PyConAU. <em>Speaker</em>
</li>
<li>
RailsConf. <em>Speaker</em>
</li>
<li>
RubyConfAU. <em>Speaker</em>
</li>
</ul>

<h4>2012</h4>

<ul>
<li>
Confident Coding. <em>Speaker</em>
</li>
<li>
GoGaRuCo. <em>Speaker</em>
</li>
</ul>]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>760</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2014-04-18 03:13:12]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2014-04-18 03:13:12]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[upcoming]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[page]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
</channel>
</rss>
